# Alexandre Rieux

alexrieux.com

W3 8TF London, UK +447943877833 alexr.3165@gmail.com

### **SKILLS**

Javascript / Typescript / Swift

NodeJS / Python / Golang

AWS, GCP, k8s, Terraform

Kafka, BigQuery, MySQL, PostgresSQL

Line management

Software architecturing

Declarative programming

UI and UX design

Project and product management

Agile methodologies

### **PROJECTS**

### monumap.com

A web application to get travel inspiration from UNESCO sites.

#### React-mapbox-gl

A React library allowing React developers to build declarative mapbox-gl maps.

#### Teazeit

An IOS application allowing users to facilitate private events

# Technical lead engineer

Experienced technical lead engineer who enjoy working in an agile environment where engineering practices facilitate product features and enhance the user experience. Understanding the business domain of the company I work for is as essential as mastering the best engineering tools.

### **EXPERIENCE**

# CF, Technical Lead Engineer

London (UK), July 2021 - Current

- Setup platform foundation on AWS.
- · Built and maintained React and Python apps
- Built an engineering career framework.
- Designed 2 teams, built hiring plan and led interviews.
- · Line managed multiple team members
- Promoted agile ways of working, ensuring good adoption
- Led and orchestrated development of the product, provided product, technical insight and managed communication with stakeholders

Tools: React, Redux, Typescript, Rxjs, Redux-observable, Webpack, Functional Programming, NodeJS, CI / CD

### Kaluza (OVO Energy), Principal Engineer

London (UK), November 2020 - July 2021

- Built and maintained event driven services in Python and NodeJS for Markets team
- · Lead development of the company public API
- Built and maintained a data ingestor to feed in Bigquery from Kafka topics owned by all the teams
- Mentored engineers with pair programming and knowledge transfer workshops

# Senior Software Engineer

London (UK), July 2019 - November 2020

- Built and maintained event driven services in Python and Node
- Technical breakdown of product epics and stories including orchestrating architectural session with the team.
- Setup the a team including 2 engineers and 1 data scientist
- Built internal kafka tools used by multiple teams
- Maintained a React web dashboard and multiple JS libraries

Tools: NodeJS, Python, Kafka, GCP, Kubernetes, Terraform, PostgresSQL, Kibana, BigQuery, Redis, React, D3JS, GraphQL

### **EDUCATION**

# Master of creative design and software project management

IMIE, Rennes (France) 2013 - 2015

# Bachelor of digital design and web development

Universitée Paul Sabatier III, Tarbes (France) 2010 - 2013

### **LANGUAGES**

French Native

English Full profesionnal proficiency

German Elementary proficiency

### **INTERESTS**

Hiking, skiing, cycling, diving

Science

Interactive design

Maps and traveling

### **EXPERIENCE**

# Onthedot (Citysprint), Tech Lead Engineer

London (UK), March 2018 - July 2019

- Technical lead of a team of 5 software engineers and line managed 2 engineers
- Built and maintained an internal web dashboard and a web desktop booking platform
- Built and maintained multiple NodeJS and Golang services
- Improved velocity of the team and deliveries by improving engineering pratices (CI/CD, Testing, Technical breakdown)

Tools: React, Typescript, FP, NodeJS, Golang, AWS, DynamoDB, PusherJS, CircleCI, Concourse

## Trainline, Senior Software Engineer

London (UK), October 2016 - March 2018

First engineer to setup the new trainline.com FE platform built in React, Redux and Node with ExpressJS. Mentored and onboarded 20 engineers to build the new platform. Successfully delivered the new FE web app increasing conversion and delivering better UX. Also built an OSS library (react-skeletor) and wrote multiple technical blog posts.

Tools: React, Redux, Typescript, Rxjs, Redux-observable, Webpack, Functional Programming, NodeJS, CI / CD

### Pie (DPD), Frontend Software Engineer

London (UK), October 2015 - October 2016

Built a fleet management web application.

Tools: React, Flux, ImmutableJS, RxJS, REST, Functional Programming, Swift

## Klaxoon, Frontend Software Engineer

Rennes (FR), September 2014 - October 2015

Built multiple web application.

Tools: Javascript, BackboneJS, PHP, Objective-c, NodeJS

### Kelbillet, Frontend / iOS Developer

Rennes (FR), May 2014 - September 2014

Designed and built multiple Web app and built an IOS app

Tools: Swift, Objective-c, PHP, Javascript, Photoshop